Guide to the Mary Arden Hauss Collection, 1926-1929
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Mary Arden Hauss collection 1926-1929
University Archives, Duke University
Hauss, Mary Arden.
1.0 Linear Feet 10 Items
Mary Arden Hauss gradated from Duke University in 1929.
The collection includes one scrapbook page and other items from her time as a Duke student. The collection ranges in date from 1926-1929.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Mary Arden Hauss Collection was received by the University Archives as a gift in 2008.
Biographical Note
Mary Arden Hauss, of Thomasville, NC, graduated from Duke University in 1929. While a student, Hauss was involved in numerous activities. She was a member of the Omicron Beta Chapter of Sigma Tau Delta, the Omicron Chapter of Alpha Delta Pi, the Beta of North Carolina Chapter of Phi Beta Kappa, and the Alpha Tau Chapter of Kappa Delta Pi, and Eko-L. Additionally, Hauss was an Associate Editor of both The Archive and The Chronicle and was Vice President of Women's Student Government. She was also a member of the Taurian Players.
Collection Overview
The collection includes memorabilia from Hauss' time as a Duke University student. The is one scrapbook page that refers to "Rushing parties" on one side and has examination questions from a 1926 history exam and A Christmas Carol program (as presented by Prof. H. E. Spence) on the back. There is also a badge, graduation card, commencement invitation, and other items. The collection ranges in date from 1926-1929.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Hauss, Mary Arden
Duke University -- Alumni and alumnae
Duke University -- Students -- Societies, etc.
Duke University -- Sports
Sigma Tau Delta. Omicron Beta Chapter (Duke University)
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Scrapbook page, 1926 (Box 1)
  - Letter [Hauss invited to pose for "Faire Ladies" section of the Chanticleer], 1929
  - Commencement Program Card and Commencement Week Invitation, 1929
  - Omicron Beta Chapter, Sigma Tau Delta, Certificate, 1928
  - Duke University Athletic Association Ticketbook, 1926
  - Graduation Card, circa 1929
  - Basketball Schedule, 1926
  - Duke University Logos, undated
  - North Carolina Collegiate Press Association Badge, 1928